SEAN HARRIGAN

EPIDEMIOLOGIST & RESEARCH SCIENTIST

CONTACT	
ORCID : 0000-0001-6021-7402	
sean.pat.harrigan@gmail.com	
seanharrigan.github.io/website	/
Vancouver, BC	
SKILLS	
RESEARCH METHODS	
DATA SICENCE	
STATISTICS	
SCIENTIFIC WRITING	
EDUCATION	
MSc, Population and Public Health	
University of British Columbia	
2019-2021	
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics	
University of Victoria	
2013-2017	
CERTIFICATES	
Machine Learning and AI (2023)	
University of Toronto (9 mos.)	
Data Science (2022)	
University of British Columbia (9 mo	s.)
LANGUAGES	
R	
Python ————	
HTML —	
Bash	

ABOUT ME

I am a dedicated and passionate worker who loves to learn. My background includes various research roles related to health in academia, industry and volunteer positions, with a focus in methodology, data / statistical analysis and academic writing. I have a passion for health science research as well as data science, specifically data analysis and data visualisaiton.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Epidemiologist

BC Centre for Disease Control

2021-Present

- Focused on design and methodology of research projects, data and statistical analysis, and scientific writing
- Conceptualising and conducting all aspects of epidemiologic research studies (i.e. hypotheses, study population, methodology, analysis, etc.)
- Leading the statistical analysis in R, including exploratory analyses as well as creating data analysis pipelines from tidying raw data, applying causal frameworks and to modelling severity outcomes
- Leading the scientific writing of manuscripts for internal use and for publication in scientific journals

Researcher & Primary Data Analyst

University of British Columbia

2020-2021

- Initiative focused in occupational health and safety oh health workers, in Vancouver at the start of the COVID-19 pandemic
- Co-lead a study in collaboration with the World Health
 Organization which surveyed health care workers from around
 world about risks and protection measures in the workplace
 during the pandemic
- Created a database of all physicians and collect data on exposures and test results to monitor physicians and other healthcare workers in Vancouver throughout the pandemic

Research Associate

Broadstreet Health Economics and Outcomes Research 20

- 2017-2019
- Co-lead a systematic review on a rare disease and have coauthored a meta-analysis on drug effectiveness
- Conducted a systematic literature review and network metaanalysis, including abstract review and data extraction
- Collaborator and pharmaceutical clients in relation to the research projects
- Completed 2 courses from York University in Health Economic Modelling in R: decision analysis and Markov models (10 weeks)